Guide to Dorothy Delay Oral History by Keeley Brooks
Dorothy DeLay Oral History by Keeley Brooks
Oral History of American Music
Dorothy DeLay Oral History by Keeley Brooks
2024
DD
Oral History of American Music
1 Computer File
172 megabytes
Brooks, Keeley
Scope and Contents
This collection is an in-progress oral history on the violin pedagogue Dorothy DeLay (March 31, 1917 – March 24, 2002), who taught at several music conservatories, including the Juilliard School, University of Cincinnati College-Conservatory of Music, during the mid- to late 20th century. The interviews were conducted by Yale undergraduate Keeley Brooks, as the basis of her 2025 senior thesis.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research. The finding aid includes links to stream most interviews online via Oral History of American Music's (OHAM) AV access system, Aviary. Yale users can login to Aviary using their Yale University ID, to stream these interviews without restriction. Other users are able to request access to interviews directly through Aviary. For access instructions,, see OHAM's website.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically by surname.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
.wav files
Violin teachers; Women violinists; Violinists United States; DeLay, Dorothy, 1917-2002
- Iwazumi, Ray
  - Iwazumi, Ray, 2024 May 10; DD 1 a; Brooks, Keeley; 1 Computer File; 172 megabytes; Approximate running time: 47 minutes
    Scope and Contents
    Interview conducted over videochat, with interviewee in New York, NY and interviewer in New Haven, CT
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    .wav file
    Iwazumi, Ray; DeLay, Dorothy, 1917-2002
- Kim Chee-Yun
  - Kim Chee-Yun, 2024 June 9; DD 2 a; Brooks, Keeley; 1 Computer File; 144 megabytes; Approximate running time: 39 mins
    Kim, Chee-Yun, 1970-; DeLay, Dorothy, 1917-2002
- Lin Cho-Liang
  - Lin Cho-Liang, 2024 June 19; DD 3 a; Brooks, Keeley; 1 Computer File; 181 megabytes; Approximate running time: 50 mins
    DeLay, Dorothy, 1917-2002
- Mills, Jesse
  - Mills, Jesse, 2024 June 18; Brooks, Keeley; 1 Computer File; 389 megabytes; Approximate running time: 39 mins
    .wav files
- Priday, Rachel Lee
  - Priday, Rachel Lee, 2024 July 23; DD 4 a; Brooks, Keeley; 1 Computer File; 3.75 megabytes; Approximate running time: 39 mins